Guide to the James Weldon Johnson Collection Files
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- "M"
  - McKim, J. Miller, 2 autograph letters, signed, to Samuel J. May, 1866 February 25 and March 30 (Box 10, Folder 221)
  - McPherson, Nenien C., Jr., "The Negro in Our Midst," an article, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 10, Folder 222)
  - McWilliams, Carey, Lawson & Trumbo vs. United States, June 1949, mimeographed typescript, 1949 June (Box 10, Folder 223)
    Amicus Curiae brief. On the government inquiry into the motion picture industry and its imposed censorhsip and violation of the first amendment.
  - Maddox, Herman Gregory, Siren of the Water Front, typescript, original, with the author's manuscript corrections and revisions, a short story, undated (Box 10, Folder 224)
  - Major, Clarence, American Set Up, poems, typescript, xerox copy, with the author's manuscript corrections, poems, as edited by Norman Holmes Pearson for the Wesleyan Press, undated (Box 11, Folder 225)
    Gift of Norman Holmes Pearson.
  - Maloney, Lionel, poems, typescripts, originals and carbons, undated (Box 11, Folder 226)
    Poems include: "Barbados!," "A Cog Dream," "Fable," "Insomnia," "Lyre," "On Being a Rolling Stone," "On Life," "Rainy Day Symphony," "To the Lost Years," "Two Against One," and signed "Love Was a Symphony."
  - Mannix, Daniel Pratt, Kibiko, typescript, carbon, The Kind Knife, original title, undated (Box 11, Folder 227)
    Gift of the Book of the Month Club.
  - Marshall, Thurgood, "Statement by Thurgood Marshall, Representing the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Before the Joint Committee of the Ives-Quinn Bill to Prohibit Discrimination in Employment," typescript, copy, 1945 February 20 (Box 11, Folder 228)
    Speech delivered on behalf of the NAACP, February 20, 1945.
  - Matheus, John F.
    - Ouanga!, libretto, typescript, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 229)
      Libretto by John Frederich Matheus, music by Clarence Cameron White. Includes mailing envelope addressed to Carl Van Vechten, dated 1940
    - Ouanga!, The Story of a Negro Opera, typescript, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 230)
    - Ti Yette, typescript. A play in one-act, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 231)
      Gift of Dorothy Peterson, 1942.
  - Maudelle, autograph note, signed, to Ann, written on the back of a dance recital program, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 232)
  - May, Samuel
    See also: Pillsbury, Parker; McKim, J. Miller
    - Garrison, William Lloyd, autograph letter, signed, to Garrison, Leicester, 1876 May 7 (Box 11, Folder 233)
    - James Munroe & Co., autograph letter, signed, to James Munroe & Co., Syracuse, 1846 September 10 (Box 11, Folder 234)
  - Mencken, Henry L., 1927-50
    - Schuyler, George, 45 typed letters, signed, to Schuyler, 1927-32 (Box 11, Folder 235)
    - Schuyler, George, 38 typed letters, signed, to Schuyler, 1933-38 (Box 11, Folder 236)
    - Schuyler, George, 34 typed letters, signed, to Schuyler, 1939-50 (Box 11, Folder 237)
  - Meekins, Theodore, typescripts, original, signed. Dedicated to James Weldon Johnson, undated (Box 11, Folder 238)
    Poems include "What Land is This?" and "Soul's Triumph."
  - Menken, Adah Isaacs, The World's Delight: The Story of Adah Isaacs Menken, typescript, written by John S. Kendall, The Louisiana Historical Society, Vol. 21, 1938 January-October (Box 11, Folder 239)
  - Merriam, Eve, 1 typed letter, signed, to Mrs. Untermeyer, 1956 June 7 (Box 11, Folder 240)
  - Mezzrow, Milton and Bernard Wolfe, Really the Blues, typescript, carbon and original, with the author's manuscript corrections and revisions, on jazz music, 1946; 2 (Box 12, Folder 241-242)
    Gift of Bernard Wolfe, 1950.
  - Miller, Lucille, Plans for the birthday celebration in memory of James Weldon Johnson, June 17, 1942, autograph manuscript and typescript, original (Box 12, Folder 243)
    Includes list of invitees and opening prayer in tribute to Johnson. With 2 autograph notes signed by Grace Nail Johnson.
  - Moody, Laing, printed circular for the purpose of forming an impartial suffrage association, Boston, signed and filled in by the secretary, Laing Moody, 1866 March 22 (Box 12, Folder 244)
  - Moore, Fred R., autograph letters, signed, 1920-1933, undated (Box 12, Folder 245)
    1 autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Moore from J. Boddy, dated July 1920. Sent with April 1920 issue of The National Geographic Magazine with annotations by Boddy. 1 typed letter, signed, from Norman Eustace Cameron to the editor of the New York Age, Fred R. Moore, dated December 4, 1930. 1 typed letter, signed, from Charles E. Hall to Fred E. Moore, dated June 9, 1933. 1 autograph letter, signed, from Archibald Johnson to Mr. Moore, dated July 15, 1929. Sent with article clipping, "A Bolshevik in Abyssinia." 1 autograph letter, signed, from Archibald Johnson to editor of the New York Age, Fred R. Moore, undated.
    See also: Rosemond, Henri
  - Morgan, David R., Six Weeks' Course in New Testament Interpretation, mimeographed typescript, copy 4, with an autograph note by Langston Hughes on the first leaf, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 246)
  - Morris Brown College, "Cooperation between Morris Brown College, Atlanta University, and other colleges, 1932/33-1933-34," typescript, carbon and original, circa 1938 (Box 12, Folder 247)
    Includes 2 typed letters, carbon copies, from others concerning the proposal.
  - Moton, Robert Russa, 5 typed letters, signed, to Josephine DeWitt, 1931-34 (Box 12, Folder 248)
  - Muir, Lewis F., "Have a Heart," autographed piano score, original pencil score, with mimeographed lyrics for Muir's "I Didn't Want to Fall in Love", undated (Box 12, Folder 249)
  - Murray, Albert, South to a Very Old Place, unrevised page proofs, xerox copy. Published: New York, McGraw-Hill, 1971. (Box 12, Folder 250)
  - Murray, Pauli, 1 typed letter, signed, to Miss Surkin, 1934 September 28 (Box 12, Folder 251)
- "N"
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, reports, minutes of meetings, typescripts, carbons, 1930-1937 (Box 13, Folder 252)
    Includes recommendations for the 1937 Spingarn Medal.
  - National Colored Protective Association, 1 typed letter, signed, to L. L. Pratt, August 8, Jacksonville, Florida, concerning the NAACP Silent Parade, circa 1916 (Box 13, Folder 253)
  - New York City Public School 113, "We Honor James Weldon Johnson," tribute book to James Weldon Johnson, written and illustrated by students from Public School 113, autograph manuscripts, signed, and original crayon drawings, 1944 April 5 (Box 13, Folder 254)
  - Norford, George, Joy Exceeding Glory, typescript, carbon, a play in three acts, undated (Box 13, Folder 255)
- "O"
  - O'Brien, Robert W., The Brown Thrush: Anthology of Verse by Negro Students from Talladega and Tougaloo Colleges, proof sheets, folded, edited by O' Brien and Lillian W. Voorhees, with the editor's corrections and revisions, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 256)
    Includes an additional typed leaf laid in. Published: Lawson-Roberts Co., Claremont, California, 1932.
  - Okala, Ollie Jewel, postcard written and signed by Olyve Jeter Haynes (Mrs. George Edmund Haynes), to Okala, 1979 February 16 (Box 13, Folder 257)
  - Osborn, Samuel
    - 1 autograph letter, signed, to H.G. Feltus, undated (Box 13, Folder 258)
    - Affidavit regarding a runaway slave, autograph manuscript, copy, accusing Dr. Osborn of cutting off his slave's ear with immoral and criminal intent, 1809 November 13 (Box 13, Folder 259)
    - To the readers of the Long Island Star, reprint of a letter, Brooklyn, New York, 1809 November 3-11 (Box 13, Folder 260)
      Includes a reprint of a reply from Charles Ball to the readers (of the Long Island Star ), November 11, 1809, Brooklyn, on the verso of the above leaf and continuing on a second leaf, concerning Dr. Osborn's character and medical ethics
- "P"
  - Parker, Lorenzo D.
    - "Memorable Hours in a Classroom," autograph manuscript signed, carbon, on her impressions of James Weldon Johnson as a teacher, undated (Box 13, Folder 261)
      Gift of the author, 1952 September 1.
    - Short stories, typescripts, original, signed L.D. Becket, with the author's manuscript corrections in pen, written for James Weldon Johnson's class in Creative Literature, Fisk University, with pencil revisions in Dr. Johnson's hand, 1936 February 20, April 28 (Box 13, Folder 262)
      Gift of the author, 1952 July 24.
  - Parks, H. B., 1 autograph letter, signed, to C. N. Douglass, Missoula, Montana, 1915 November 1 (Box 13, Folder 263)
  - Paton, Alan, Too Late the Phalarope, typescripts, carbon, advance copy submitted to the Book-of-the-Month Club, undated (Box 13, Folder 264)
    Gift of the Book-of-the-Month Club, 1955.
  - Patterson, W. R., Poems, typescripts, original, signed, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 265)
    Poems include: "Welcome Mr. Hughes," "A Toast to Mother," "A Song of the Negro Soldier Boy," "Dearest Pal of Mine," and "School is Out." Presented to Langston Hughes, January 15, 1944, at a dinner in his honor at the Colored High School, Lawton, Oklahoma, of which Patterson was principal.
  - Patton, E. E., "Life is a Puzzle," typescript, carbon, poem, sent to James Weldon Johnson, 1935 January 4 (Box 13, Folder 266)
  - Peterkin, Mrs. Julia Mood, Scarlet Sister Mary, typescript, carbon, with manuscript corrections and annotations, play acted in by Rose McClendon, 1930 December 10 (Box 13, Folder 267)
  - Peterson, Jerome Bowers
    - "Negroes in U.S. Foreign Service Over Seventy Years, Diplomatic and Consular Officers," typescript, carbon, 1942 September 15 (Box 13, Folder 268)
    - "Frederick Douglass," autograph manuscript, poem of one 8-line stanza, undated (Box 13, Folder 269)
    - Tribute to Jerome B. Peterson, typescript, original, autograph manuscript, circa 1943 (Box 13, Folder 270)
      Written by Helen M. Boardman. Includes autograph letter, signed, from J. Mitchell Moore, assistant editor for The Nation, to Miss Boardman, rejecting the piece for publication, dated November 23, 1943.
      Gift of the author.
  - Peterson, Sidney
    - 2 typed letters, signed, from Numa P. G. Adams, 1 letter inviting Dr. Peterson to the First Annual Conference of Negro Tuberculosis Workers at Howard University, with list of participants included, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 271)
    - 1 typed letter, signed, from William H. Hastie to Peterson, 1937 June 28 (Box 13, Folder 272)
    - 1 autograph letter, signed, from Carl Van Vechten, 1930 October 31 (Box 13, Folder 273)
  - Pettiford, J. V. R., 1 typed letter, signed, to unidentified correspondent, Birmingham, Alabama, 1910 June 11, undated (Box 13, Folder 274)
    Includes press release for The White Man's Burden, written by Dr. B.F. Riley, circa 1910. Also includes hand drawn map, "from memory of the northern portion of the citadel, showing where the flint locks may be found."
  - Phillips, Wendell, 5 autograph letters, signed, to Mr. Child, Miss Duncan, Mr. Hart, Gerrit Smith, and an unidentified correspondent, 1860-1969, undated (Box 13, Folder 275)
  - Pickens, William, 2 typed letters, signed, to Josephine DeWitt, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 276)
  - Pillsbury, Parker, 2 autograph letters, signed, to Samuel May, December 21, and an unidentified correspondent, November 14, 1884 (Box 13, Folder 277)
  - Pinkett, Louise L., poems, typescript, original, signed, undated (Box 13, Folder 278)
    Poems include: "Mysterious Lady," "Sunset," "Denial," and "Loneliness." The poem "Sunset" has a manuscript note by James Weldon Johnson, to whom the poems were sent.
  - Pivano-Sottsass, Fernanda
    - "Literature of Colored America," typescript, carbon, with a few author's manuscript corrections, 1950 June 9 (Box 13, Folder 279)
      Lecture delivered at the Unione Culturale, Turin, Italy, June 9, 1950, on the occasion of "Settimana Einaudi Week." Accompanied by a printed invitation to the lecture.
    - "La Letteratura Dei Negri D'America," typescript, carbon, with the author's corrections, 1950 June 9 (Box 13, Folder 280)
  - Plummer, Jewel Isadora, "My Dolls and Teddy Bear," typescript, original, corrected, poem sent to James Weldon Johnson, undated (Box 13, Folder 281)
  - Poppel, Esther N., "Three Aprils Have I Known," poem, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 13, Folder 282)
    Gift of Frances O. Grant, September 1977.
  - Powell, Adam Clayton Jr.
  - Price, Leontyne, 1 typed letter, signed, to Aileen Pringle, with 1 envelope, on her concert schedule, 1961 September 23 (Box 13, Folder 283)
- "R"
  - Randolph, Richetta G., "James Weldon Johnson," typescript, undated (Box 14, Folder 284)
    Biographical statement describing Johnson's activities through 1929, by his secretary.
  - Rapier, James T., "Notes of Travel in Europe," autograph manuscript, notebook, covering his trip to Vienna in 1873 as representative from Alabama to the World's Fair, image of Rapier affixed to cover page of notebook (Box 14, Folder 285)
    Gift of Mrs. Jas R. White, 1944.
  - Rawls, Isetta Crawford, poems, typescripts, original, signed, undated (Box 14, Folder 286)
    Poems include "But for Those," "The Liar's Creed," and "Just Like Mama Does."
  - Rea, James M., "True Land Tenure=True Monetary System," typescript, original, undated (Box 14, Folder 287)
    With an autograph note, signed, from James Weldon Johnson to "F.M.," on a printed card from the Chicago Tribune rejecting Rea's article for publication.
  - Redding, J. Saunders
    - To Make A Poet Black, typescript, carbon and original, with the author's corrections and additions, published: Chapel Hill, The University of North Carolina Press, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 288)
    - ---, typescript, carbon, signed, with the author's manuscript notations, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 289)
    - ---, galley proofs, signed, with the author's manuscript notations, corrections and additions, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 290)
  - Reines, Bernard, Forward the Heart, reproduced from typewritten copy, a play in three acts, performed in 1949 (Box 14, Folder 291)
  - Revels, Fleming R., signature, as subscriber for printed copies of speech of Representative of Ohio William Lawrence's "The Georgia Bill", 1870 March 5 (Box 14, Folder 292)
    Gift of Carl Van Vechten, July 1960.
  - Rhambo, Lilly C., poems, autograph manuscripts, signed, undated (Box 14, Folder 293)
    Poems include "Dismal Day" and "Negro American."
  - Richer, Clement, "L' Homme de la Caravelle," typescript, original and carbon, with the author's manuscript corrections and an original drawing of a map laid in, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 294)
    Inscribed by Richer to Carl Van Vechten. Published: Paris, Librairie Plon, 1952.
  - Robeson, Eslanda Goode, 10 letters to Harold Jackman, 1 autograph letter, signed, first part missing, 2 autograph letters, signed, intact, 7 typed letters, signed, intact, 1932-1939 (Box 14, Folder 295)
  - Robeson, Paul, "Account of Commencement Day Exercises at Morehouse College," with excerpts of speeches by Benjamin E. Mays, president, and Paul Robeson, recipient of degree of doctor of humane letters, transcript, reproduced from typewritten copy, as broadcast by West Indian Radio, with note by Langston Hughes: "Interview with Paul Robeson", 1943 June 18 (Box 14, Folder 296)
  - Rosemond, Henri, autograph letter, signed, to Fred R. Moore, 1931 June 10 (Box 14, Folder 297)
  - Rustin, Monroe C., poems for Miss D.E. Emerson, autograph manuscripts, signed, contains two poems, undated (Box 14, Folder 298)
- "S"
  - Sarvis, Mary Alice, poems, typescripts, original, undated (Box 14, Folder 299)
    Poems include "In Mad Autumn Weather," "Spring," "Loot," "Hills at Dusk," "To April," and "Untitled." With autograph note in unidentified hand on 2nd leaf.
  - Schuyler, George
    See: Mencken, Henry L.
  - Seward, William H., 1 autograph letter, signed, to Brantz Mayer, 1840 May 19 (Box 14, Folder 300)
  - Slavery, 5 bills of sale, 1 receipt, and 1 estate inventory (including slaves), with typed copies of two of the bills of sale, 1856 February 7-June 10 (Box 14, Folder 301)
  - Smith, Gerrit, 1 autograph note signed for autograph album, Washington, 1834 January 20 (Box 15, Folder 302)
    See also: Phillips, Wendell
  - Smith, Goldwin, 1 autograph letter, signed, to Boston Advertiser, 1865 (Box 15, Folder 303)
  - Sottong, Agnes M.
    - Various correspondents, 1942-1943 (Box 15, Folder 304)
      Contains: 1 typed letter to Judge Jane Bolin; 3 typed letters, signed, from Jane Bolin; 1 typed letter, signed, from May E. Chinn, M.D.; 1 typed letter, signed, from Anna Arnold Hedgeman; 1 typed letter, signed, from Dorothy I. Height; 1 typed letter to Miss Vivian Mason; 2 typed letters, signed, from Vivian Mason.
    - Bethune, Mary MacLeod, 1942-1943 (Box 15, Folder 305)
      Contains 2 typed letters, signed, from Mary MacLeod Bethune.
    - Carter, Elmer Anderson, 1942-1943 (Box 15, Folder 306)
      Contains: 3 typed letters, signed, from Carter and 1 typed letter to Carter.
    - Carver, George Washington, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 307)
      Contains: 1 typed letter, signed, from Carver and 1 typed letter, signed, to Carver.
    - Granger, Lester B., 1942-1943 (Box 15, Folder 308)
      Contains: 3 letters, signed, from Granger and 1 letter typed to Granger.
    - Powell, Adam Clayton, Jr., 1 typed letter, signed, from Powell, 1943 January 22 (Box 15, Folder 309)
    - Stokes, Olivia P., 1942 (Box 15, Folder 310)
      Contains: 2 typed letters, signed, from Stokes and 1 typed letter to Stokes.
    - Tobias, Channing H., 1 autograph letter, signed, from Tobias, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 311)
  - Spellman, A. B., 1 typed letter, signed, to Diane Di Prima, with addressed envelope, on the printing of his The Beautiful Days, 1969 May 28 (Box 15, Folder 312)
    J.W.J. Fund, October 1973.
  - Spencer, Anne, 1 copy of autograph letter, signed, from Roy Basler, chief of the Library of Congress, 1972 November 16 (Box 15, Folder 313)
  - Spencer, Chauncey
    - Untitled poem, autograph manuscript, poem of fifteen lines, beginning with the line "When you feel down...", undated (Box 15, Folder 314)
    - 1 typed letter, signed, from John Melville Jenning, Viriginia Historical Society; 1 typed letter, signed, from Junius R. Fishburne, Virginia Historic Landmarks Commission, 1976 June (Box 15, Folder 315)
  - Spingarn, Arthur B.
    See: Handy, William C.
  - Stevenson, Janet and Philip, Declaration, reproduced from a typewritten copy, a play in three acts, Philip Stevenson, joint author, 1948; 2 (Box 15, Folder 316-317)
    Copy 1: Gift of Harold Jackman. See HJ to CVV 04/26/57. Copy 2: Gift of Langston Hughes.
  - Still, Verna Arvey, "Famous Author Gives Negro Collection to Yale," typescript, carbon, on Carl Van Vechten and the establishment of the James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection, undated (Box 15, Folder 318)
  - Stokes, Olivia P.
  - Sullivan, Noel
    See: Hayes, Roland
  - Sumner, Charles
    - ---, George, 1857, 1861 (Box 15, Folder 319)
      Contains: 1 autograph letter, signed, to George, Boston, August 6, 1857; 1 autograph letter, signed, to unnamed correspondent, "Senate Chamber," July 8, 1861.
    - Hale, Mr., 1 autograph letter, signed, to Hale, undated (Box 15, Folder 320)
    - Lyon, Mr., 1 autograph letter, signed, to Lyon, 1863 (Box 15, Folder 321)
    - R., Mr., 1 autograph letter, signed, to R., 1863 (Box 15, Folder 322)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 2 autograph letters, signed, to unidentified correspondents, 1857, 1861 (Box 15, Folder 323)
  - Sutton, Dorothy, poems, typescripts, original, undated (Box 15, Folder 324)
    Poems include: "Dreams," "The Night Wind," "Star Diamonds," "To a Bethrothed," "Escapade," "To a Muse," "Memories," "River," "Happiness," "Remember," and untitled poems whose first lines are "When I can live as Christ...," "I sang of love...," and "Sing merrily, sing merrily...".
- "T"
  - Taggard, Genevieve, "Proud Day," poem, autograph manuscript, fair copy, with the subtitle: "Marian Anderson on the steps of the Lincoln Memorial", undated (Box 15, Folder 325)
    Published: The Crisis, Vol. 47, October 1940, and later in her book, Long View, New York, Harper & Brothers, 1942. Accompanied by a typed letter, signed, from Kenneth Durant to the Yale University Library, May 24, 1950, New York, NY, forwarding the manuscript, with typed letter acknowledging receipt.
    Also includes "Proud Day," typescript, original, draft with the author's revisions.
    Gift of Mrs. Robert M. Liles, 1950 May.
  - Talbot, Edith Armstrong
    - Children of One Father: A Story of the New South, typescript, original, with a few author's revisions, undated (Box 15, Folder 326)
    - Pilgrim's Progress: A Dramatized Modern Version, typescript, original, with a few author's revisions, undated (Box 15, Folder 327)
    - The World Reborn; Or, Children of One Father, typescript, original, with a few author's revisions, undated (Box 15, Folder 328)
  - Taliaferro, James Mercedes, poems, typescripts, original, signed, also signed "Jymmie", undated (Box 15, Folder 329)
    Poems include "Life" and "???"
  - Tanner, Henry O., 4 autograph letters, signed, to Mrs. Mandella Bonsfield, with addressed envelopes, 1935-1945, undated (Box 15, Folder 330)
    Also includes "Tea tendered to Tanner" announcement page, signed by Tanner.
  - Tappen, Francis, 1 autograph letter, signed, to David T. Kimball, New Haven, 1883 July 19 (Box 15, Folder 331)
  - Tarry, Ellen, 1974, undated
    - The Runaway Elephant, setting typescript, original, with the author's revisions and with the publisher's editorial markings, a children's story, circa 1950, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 332)
      Accompanied by 1 typed letter, signed, and 1 autograph letter, signed, to Miss Tarry from miscellaneous correspondents and a mimeographed elementary school program on Black History Week, February 21, 1974.
      Gift of Ellen Tarry, 1950.
    - My Dog Rinty, drafts, typescripts, original, signed, corrected and revised, Marie Hall Ets, joint author, a children's story, circa 1946 (Box 15, Folder 333)
      Early draft titled David Lives in Harlem. In a case with original photographs by Alexander and Alexandria Alland.
  - Tate, Ernest C., The Social Implications of the Writings and the Career of James Weldon Johnson, typescript, carbon, outline of a proposed thesis (Ph.D.), New York University, March 15, 1949, published: New York, The American Press, c. 1968, 1949 March 15 (Box 16, Folder 334)
  - Tate, Merze, The Disarmament Illusion: The Movement for Limitation of Armaments to 1907, typescript, carbon, thesis (Ph.D.), Harvard University, July, 1940, published: New York, Macmillian Co., 1942, 1940 July (Box 16, Folder 335)
  - Taylor, Prentiss
    See: Alexander, Mrs. John W. Kelly, Welbourn
  - Thiell, Mary E., Alice and Mandy in Days Work, play, typescripts, carbon, includes duplicate copies, incomplete., undated (Box 16, Folder 336)
    Play in which Rose McClendon and Hugh Jackman acted.
  - Thomas, Gertrude Allison, typescripts, carbon, undated (Box 16, Folder 337)
    Poems include "My Aviator" and "A Tribute."
  - Tobias, Channing H.
  - Toucey, Charles T., 1 autograph letter, signed, to J. W. Alden, Baltimore, 1844 September 28 (Box 16, Folder 338)
  - Toucey, I., 1 autograph letter, signed, to N. Caxen (Mass.), Washington, 1857 January 6 (Box 16, Folder 339)
  - Tourgee, Albion W., autograph card, with note that reads "This 2nd day of May 1890, is my 52nd birthday", 1890 May 2 (Box 16, Folder 340)
    Purchased with copy of A Fool's Errand, JWJ Fund.
  - Turner, John Adolph, autograph manuscript and typescript, original, undated (Box 16, Folder 341)
    Poems include "My Life," "Compensation," "To My Wife," and "To My Daughter."
- "V"
  - Van Doren, Irita, 1 typed letter, signed, to Walter White, 1933 February 3 (Box 16, Folder 342)
  - Van Dyke, Henry
    - Ladies of the Rachmaninoff Eyes, typescript, carbon and original, signed, first draft, corrected and revised, undated (Box 16, Folder 343)